ntsb.gov 2018-06-14

# Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) Web site and reviewing our privacy policy. 

Our privacy policy is clear: We collect no personally identifiable information when you visit our Web site unless you specifically and knowingly provide that information to us. 

Personally identifiable information includes your name, e-mail, mailing address, phone number, or other information that identifies you personally. The Privacy Act of 1974 establishes certain controls over what personal information is collected by the National Transportation Safety Board how it is used. 

The following web page provides additional information on your rights under the Privacy Act: <http://www.pueblo.gsa.gov/cic_text/fed_prog/foia/foia.htm>. 

#### Information Collected and Stored Automatically

During your visit to this web site, the NTSB utilizes Google Analytics to automatically collect certain information about your visit. We do not gather, request, record, require, collect or track any Internet users' Personal Information through these processes. You may opt out of this data collection by following the directions provided settings at [www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml](http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml).

Information collected includes:

  * The name of the domain (for example, "yourcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you are connecting from a university's domain) and IP address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet) from which you access our website; 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site; 
  * The date and time you access our site; 
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site; and 
  * The pages you visit. 

The NTSB uses this information for statistical analysis of website usage, in order to assess the use of information presented on the website, to identify improvements, and to optimize the website. Only authorized Agency web managers have access to the raw analytics data used to create reports. Aggregate statistical information, such as number of visitors or numbers of page views, may be kept indefinitely in order for the NTSB to identify trends, track metrics in order to determine the effectiveness of website content, or to provide long-term reporting on website traffic. Information is collected for NTSB internal use only, unless required to be disclosed as part of a legal investigation.

The analytics system uses a persistent cookie establish a multi-session measurement process ("Tier 2") in order to identify returning visitors and provide accurate visitor counts. A cookie is a tiny piece of data stored by a user's browser that helps a web site or service recognize that user's unique computer. You can remove or block cookies by changing the settings of your browser. USA.gov provides detailed instructions on removing and modifying your cookie settings at [www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml](http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml). Your use of NTSB.gov is not dependent on your browser accepting cookies.

#### Online Subscription/Newsletter Services and Mailing Lists

We offer a variety of listserv services, to include either NTSB News about all our products and programs, or News by Modal Offices (Aviation, Highway, Marine, Pipeline and Hazmat, and Railroad, and also the NTSB Training Center e-Newsletter.

We do not require you to provide any personal information to access our Web site or to use most of our services. If you desire to participate in one of our subscription or newsletter services we ask that you provide an email address and/or additional information to receive information provided by the service.

You may subscribe or unsubscribe to any of our several mailing lists by visiting our [Registration page](http://app.ntsb.gov/registration/registration.aspx). To subscribe you will need to provide your name and mailing address (work preferred). We retain and use mailing list information only to keep you informed about our products and services. You may log on to our Web site at any time to remove your name from the mailing list or to change and update your personal information. 

We do not rent out or sell personal information for commercial purposes. We also do not give, sell or transfer personal information to third parties, unless required by law. 

#### Contacting Us

Your comments, questions, and suggestions are extremely important to us. You may contact us electronically by completing the online request form on our [Contact page](http://app.ntsb.gov/pubmail/pubmail.aspx). You may also contact us by using the telephone numbers, mailing addresses, and e-mail addresses provided on the web site. Before contacting us, there are a few things you should know. 

You are not required to provide your name or any other personally-identifying information in order to contact us. If you want us to respond to a question or other place an inquiry, however, you will need to provide sufficient information for us to contact you. 

Our authority for collecting information when you contact us is section 301 of title 5, United States Code. 

We may forward your correspondence, including any personally identifiable information you choose to send, to other government employees or government contractors to process your request or research and answer your questions. We may also share this information with contractors for purposes of statistical analysis and may track e-mails for purposes of improving our response times and identifying message turn-around times. If you choose to transmit or receive personal information electronically, you should be aware that we cannot guarantee confidentiality across the Internet. If your communication is very sensitive you may want to send it by postal mail instead of using e-mail. 

#### Children's Privacy

This Web site does not currently offer educational content created for children.   NTSB makes no attempt to collect personally-identifiable information online from children. If a child voluntarily initiates a request for information or services through our "Contact Us" Web page, the information collected will be used solely for the purpose of responding to the request. We take children's privacy very seriously, and encourage parents to contact us with any questions or concerns they may have. 

#### Security Notification

When you access our site you are entering an Official United States Government System, which may be used only for authorized purposes. The Government may monitor and audit usage of this system, and all persons are hereby notified that use of this system constitutes consent to such monitoring and auditing. For Site Security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, we employ software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act. 

To ensure the security and confidentiality of personally identifiable information, we use security software to prevent unauthorized access, and conduct periodic tests of security safeguards. Learn more about our Security Policy.

#### Links to Other Sites

Our Web site has links to the Web sites of other federal agencies, and in a few cases, links to private organizations. Learn more about our Linking Policy here. 

Once you proceed to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. Any link to another Web site is provided solely for the convenience of the user and does not constitute endorsement by the National Transportation Safety Board or the United States Government of that site or its information, products, or services. We assume no responsibility for the content or operation of other Web sites.
